I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
I've had enough of you!
I'll take anything you can spare...
Thank you very much.
Wolf and the Grand Scheme
You're back early.
Holo.
I'm sorry.
Here are three Lumione I managed to collect by myself.
The remaining forty-four Lumione are beyond my grasp.
The only thing I can think of is to go to a gambling parlor with the money,
but you'd probably have more luck with that than I would.
If I'm going to fail, I'd rather put the money to good use.
Owing three more Lumione won't make much of a difference anyway.
You fool!
Hurry up and come back!
What's going on?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry!
I just dropped this from the window.
You've got to be kidding me.
You fool.
Sorry.
What do you mean by that?
What are you sorry for?
What would you have done if I took the money and fled?
I wouldn't have minded.
Because I failed, I won't be able to fulfill our contract.
That money would cover your travel expenses.
You... You're going to give me money... so I can keep traveling?
Y-Yeah...
I'm the one at fault, you know!
You would have been able to borrow money if not for me!
Why aren't you angry at me?
How come you're not blaming me for anything?
You followed me because you were worried about me.
I can't be angry at you for—
You fool!
You...
Watch out!
You're a sucker after all!
A... sucker?
I'm right, aren't I?
I followed you out of my selfishness.
You had every right to be mad at me.
But then you apologize just because you slapped my hands away!
You even came back to say sorry!
Because I was sorry.
I felt like I did something that couldn't be forgiven no matter how many times I apologized.
That's why I wanted to do all I could,
but it seems that only hurt you more. I'm sorry.
Would you...
Answer me this one question.
You're so kind.
W-Why is that?
My personality, I suppose.
Y-You fool!
Personality? Personality, you say?
As a male, you have to say that it's because you're in love with me, even if you don't mean it!
You fool!
S-Sorry.
To tell you the truth, I...
There are times when I want to hear sweet words even if they're a lie,
but once it's too late, hearing those words makes you want to slap the speaker's face.
Which situation do you think you're in?
T-The latter.
This is unbelievable.
I can't believe you're so softhearted!
You probably thought you'd be taking advantage of me if you said something like that, but...
It's pathetic, I know.
I still do want to hear you say it.
Let's do it over.
Why are you so kind?
Because you're special to me.
For goodness sake. What are we even doing?
Y-You're the one who made me do it!
Well, it served as good practice for you, didn't it?
Still, I must say.
Next time, just make me angry. Okay?
I appreciate the fact that you're a considerate person,
but there are things that can be settled quicker by screaming at each other.
As you wish.
So...
How much money is in the leather pouch?
Three Lumione and two-sevenths.
That means you still owe forty-three and five-sevenths, right?
I have a cunning plan.
What is it?
Don't get too excited. I don't know if it's any good.
Are you serious?
Yes. You'll be caught with certainty if you do it the usual way.
But I have an idea of how to get away with it at little risk.
R-Really?
It's okay. I'm by your side.
Yeah.
I heard you wanted to discuss something important.
Are you asking me to travel along that path?
It is slightly dangerous, but you'll be fine.
Has God not protected you up until now?
Yes.
But I've heard that mercenaries have been sighted around the area recently.
God will protect you without fail.
There's no need to worry.
Okay.
You're a wonderful shepherd.
We're all very proud of you.
Smuggling? Impossible!
I wouldn't be so sure.
You're out of your mind. Get out.
I'm sure there have been many who tried this same plan in the past,
only to be ultimately caught.
If you know that, our talk should go quickly.
People standing on the brink of ruin can't distinguish a reckless scheme from a perfect one.
That's where you are right now!
What if I tell you there's a skilled, trustworthy individual who can smuggle the gold?
A person that skilled could make plenty of money without resorting to smuggling gold, right?
It sounds too good to be true.
What if I said that this person is talented but not making good money?
Impossible.
What kind of person could fit the description you've given?
One who is skilled and employed in this town but is underpaid and in need of money.
One who is unhappy because their employer leaves something to be desired.
They're employed by the Church,
and the Church says that smuggling gold is an act of treason.
There's no doubt they'll accept the job
if it gives them an opportunity to frustrate the Church's ends while receiving compensation for their work.
The odds of betrayal are also close to zero.
I'm sure you'll be as convinced as I am when you hear the name of this person.
In that case, why don't you smuggle gold yourself?
Why would you tell me about the idea when you know that your share will become smaller as a result?
The payment deadline for my debt is today.
I'll be incarcerated by the trading house at sunset.
And I've managed to gather only this.
Take it as collateral and put your trust in me.
Here's what I want.
I request that the repayment be deferred,
and I also need you to invest your assets in the purchase of gold.
Sir?
Do you think you have the luxury of wavering?
What's that?!
Hey.
One of your men just left.
I have ears that are keen enough to unearth the deepest secrets.
The men downstairs are planning to escape this sinking ship.
See? Another one just left.
At this rate, it's only a matter of days before this shop...
Stop it!
Mr. Lemerio, what do you think?
You must know someone who can trade the smuggled gold.
Will you help us execute this plan on relatively favorable terms to you?
Mr. Lemerio!
Very well.
Let's do it.
May God forgive us.
Call Liebert.
Yes, sir.
Looks like it's my turn.
What do you mean by that?
Do you think a good-natured man like you could pull one over on that girl?
There are innocent people in this world who prefer good-natured men.
You certainly talk a lot for someone who doesn't know anything about females.
You just drove Lemerio into a corner for me.
Let me deal with her on my own.
I'm the one who ended up with worthless goods due to my own greed.
If I have you convince her so I can avoid feeling guilty, that means I'm hopeless.
Curses! And here I thought I'd be able to add to the list of favors I've done for you and cash them in later on.
Phew! That was a close one.
Hello!
Mr. Lawrence and... Miss Holo?
It must be the will of God for us to meet in front of the church.
Even I'm not that easily fooled.
Thank heavens. I've heard that lately there are those at services who have drunk too much of the Holy Blood.
I can't drink much, so I only take a little bit of the wine.
Do you have something you'd like to...
Yes, I'd like to offer you a job.
Really?
I-I mean...
Let's find a place to sit down and talk.
Okay.
Here's to our reunion!
Miss Norah, you said you could travel as far as Lamtra, right?
Y-Yes, I can.
Can you even bring your flock along?
If there aren't too many.
I'd like to hire you for a slightly unusual job.
You'll be paid twenty Lumione,
and it won't be in the form of a banknote.
I'll pay in cash.
Whoa there.
I'm sorry.
D-Did you say twenty?
Yes, twenty.
It will be on contingency due to the risks involved, though.
If you fail, you won't receive anything.
Okay.
Your job is to venture out with your sheep and return them safe and sound.
You only need to do what you normally would as a shepherd.
It must be a dangerous task
if you're willing to pay twenty Lumione.
I won't deny that.
I won't force you to accept, and I'm willing to let you think it over.
Guild membership fees are one Lumione at most, aren't they?
With twenty, you'll be able to rent a house and take care of your daily expenses, working without worry.
When the time comes, you'd even be able to obtain a business permit with ease.
Then you'd be the mistress of Norah Dressmakers.
Miss Norah, had you planned to join the tailor's guild in this city?
No, I was thinking about another town.
I see.
But the sprawling size of this city is appealing, isn't it?
It can be difficult to live in an unfamiliar town with no friends,
but you probably want to get away from the Church in this city, right?
T-That's not true.
The harder you work to protect the sheep that the church entrusts you with,
the more they suspect you of using pagan witchcraft.
Am I wrong?
They send you to places ordinary shepherds would never tread for the sake of revealing your true identity,
by claiming that safer territories are occupied by other shepherds.
I imagine that they intend to keep sending you to dangerous
places until you're attacked by wolves or mercenaries.
They'll do this day after day until they find evidence of your heathen nature.
I was a victim of a similar situation.
Let me state it clearly.
The Church of this town is lower than swine!
This is why we came up with a plan.
We'll cause a little trouble for the Church, make some money, and leave for another town.
What do you think?
What do you plan to do?
Smuggle gold.
There's no way...
How will I be involved in this?
We'll hide the gold inside the stomachs of your sheep in order to pass the checkpoints of this town.
Can you tell me the rest of plan?
The price of gold is extremely high in every town under the influence of the Church.
That's why the ideal place to get it is in the pagan town of Lamtra.
All of the safe roads leading to Lamtra are crowded with people,
and it has been the territory of other shepherds for ages.
I'd be able to travel through desolate roads without being suspected of any wrongdoing,
and that route is also the shortest distance between Lamtra and this town.
That's right.
You're being mistreated by the Church, aren't you?
This plan serves as an ideal opportunity to take revenge against them.
The Church's two biggest sources of income are tithes and the gold trade, after all.
But if we're caught, the punishments will be heavy.
And once the job is done, you'll have to leave this town to be safe.
And so...
The reward is twenty Lumione.
Please allow me to do it.
It'll be my pleasure.
Likewise.
Um...
What is it?
I wouldn't have accepted if someone else had approached me with the idea.
I decided to do it because it was you, Mr. Lawrence.
Shouldn't you be happier about this?
Everything went perfectly.
I don't care how great the profit—nothing exists to balance out the wager of a person's life.
Indeed.
And just talking up the profit like that is little different from fraud.
Merchants always say that if you get bamboozled into a bad contract, you're the fool at fault.
But who's the person we're dealing with here?
She's only a shepherd girl who doesn't know how the world works.
It's true that the girl's smile looked innocent enough.
Honestly, you're far too kind for your own good.
That little girl is not a mere lamb who exists just to be hunted and eaten.
She's a brave sheep who's decided to mingle with the predators.
She might even be a different animal wearing sheep's skin.
I don't want to admit it,
but she's a shepherd that even I approve of.
You're not in the wrong here,
so try to put others before you a bit less often.
In any case, I have to do everything I can so that we all end up laughing.
Is that so?
Would it not be better for just the two of us to have the last laugh?
I wouldn't mind that either,
but I'd prefer if we could all be happy.
There you go again.
Is that a problem?
Not at all.
Sir, are you really going to go through with this?
I have to do it.
I have to...
I don't have a choice, Liebert!
Next Episode: "Wolf and a Pack of Pups."